本字幕由诸神字幕组出品，仅供学习交流，禁止用于商业用途
更多中日双语字幕，尽在 www.kamigami.org 和微博 @诸神字幕组
日听 小伍 Cc  翻译 domi Akashi  校对 はばやし  阿布  时间轴 神埼魯蒙  压制 咸鱼
Recon Group 3
現在第三偵察隊がイタリカの代表　ピニャ・コ・ラーダ氏より
has received a request from the city of Italica's representative,
Piña Co Lada, to provide support for local peacekeeping operations.
治安維持協力要請を受け　追加支援を求めてきている
They are requesting additional support.
Special Region
Combat Team 1
Commander Colonel
Kamo
Please let me handle this!
ぜひ自分にやらせてください
Special Region
101st Company
Lieutenant Colonel
Tsuge
Combat Team 1 has finished forming up and is ready to go at any time!
第一戦闘団編成完結　すぐにでも出られます
No!
ダメだ
Special Region
Combat Team 4
Commander Colonel
Kengun
It'll take far too long to get there by ground!
地面をちんたら移動していたら　到着に時間がかかりすぎる
Lieutenant General, please pick Combat Team 4!
陸将　ぜひ私の第四戦闘団を
We've got the stereo, the loudspeakers,
Special Region
401st Company
Lieutenant Colonel
Youga
大音量スピーカーと　コンポと　ワーグナーのＣＤを用意してあります
and the Wagner CD all ready to go!
Perfect, Lieutenant Colonel Youga!
パーフェクトだ　用賀二佐
Thank you, sir!
感謝の極み
Combat Team 4 will go.
第四戦闘団の出動を命じる
What we need right now is speed.
今は速度が必要だ　それが現実的な選択だからな
So that's the sensible choice to make.
Are they possessed by the ghost of Lieutenant Colonel Kilgore?
こいつら　キルゴア中佐の霊にでも取り憑かれたのか
I can guess exactly what's going to happen now...
この後の展開が予想できるな
Thus, the JSDF Fought There!
to
kk
Thus, the JSDF Fought There!
u
ni
Thus, the JSDF Fought There!
na
to
ni
I don't really have anything I'm wishing for
特に何も望むことなんてない　身の程は知っているさ
mo
no
kk
zo
to
u
mu
kk
ko
ni
to
u
na
n
te
na
i
ni
na
mo
ni
no
mo
zo
no
mu
zo
ko
mu
to
ko
na
to
n
na
te
n
na
te
i
na
mi
no
ho
do
wa
mi
i
sh
I pretty much know my place.
i
t
te
i
no
ru
mi
sa
ho
no
do
ho
wa
do
sh
wa
i
sh
t
i
te
t
i
te
ru
i
sa
ru
so
n
na
bo
ku
so
sa
de
Even so, I think deep down that I don't wanna let anything go
そんな僕でさえも奥の方に
sa
e
om
n
ou
so
o
ku
no
na
ho
n
u
ni
bo
na
ku
bo
de
ku
sa
de
e
sa
om
e
ou
om
o
ou
ku
o
no
ku
ho
no
u
ho
ni
u
yu
zu
ri
ta
ni
It seems I'm only playing "the good girl".
ku
yu
na
譲りたくない　意向程度はあるらしい
i
ii
ko
tte
zu
i
yu
to
ha
a
ru
ra
sh
i
ri
zu
ta
ri
ku
ta
na
ku
i
na
ii
i
ko
ii
tte
ko
i
tte
to
i
ha
to
a
ha
ru
a
ra
ru
sh
ra
i
sh
ma
mo
ru
t
i
Protecting something is harder than I thought,
te
ma
an
ga
i
守るって案外と難しいね
to
mu
mo
zu
ma
ka
sh
i
ru
ne
mo
t
ru
te
t
an
te
ga
an
i
ga
to
i
mu
to
zu
mu
ka
zu
sh
ka
i
sh
ne
i
a
ki
ra
ne
But it's not like that means I'm gonna give up!
me
ru
a
wa
ke
ja
諦めるわけじゃないけど
na
i
ke
ki
do
a
ra
ki
me
ra
ru
me
wa
ru
ke
wa
ja
ke
na
ja
i
na
ke
i
do
ke
ao
i
so
ra
no
ao
ha
At the far reaches of the blue sky - the end of these connected roads,
te
t
su
青い空の果て　繋がった道の行方
na
ga
t
i
ta
ao
mi
chi
no
yu
ku
e
so
i
ra
so
no
ra
ha
no
te
ha
t
te
su
t
na
su
ga
na
t
ga
ta
t
mi
ta
chi
mi
no
chi
yu
no
ku
yu
e
ku
hi
to
wa
e
People still won't come to understand one another... but I'm fine with that
wa
ka
ri
a
人と人は分かり合えない　だけどいいんじゃない？
to
e
hi
na
i
da
ke
do
ii
n
to
ja
na
i
hi
to
wa
ka
ri
a
e
na
i
da
ke
do
ii
n
ja
na
The door I'll open will have everything changing,
i
na
hi
ra
i
ta
to
hi
bi
i
ra
開いた扉は全てを変えてゆく
hi
wa
su
be
te
i
o
ra
ka
e
ta
te
i
yu
ku
to
ta
bi
to
ra
bi
wa
ra
su
wa
be
su
te
be
o
te
ka
o
e
ka
te
e
yu
te
ku
yu
so
re
wa
a
ka
so
ku
t
Just like the break of dawn!
それは暁のように
su
re
ki
so
no
yo
u
ni
wa
re
a
wa
ka
a
t
ka
su
t
ki
su
no
ki
yo
no
u
yo
ni
u
Episode 6  Ride of the Valkyries
Defend this area with your lives!
ここを死守しろ　後はないぞ
This is our last stand!
The enemy commander is slain!
討ち取った
Listen up, men!
お前たち　これこそが戦争だ
Now this is war!
The murder and death that we sought at Alnus, which our fallen fellows never saw!
アルヌスで我らが求め　倒れた友が求めても味わえなかった　殺戮と死
敵を殺し　我らも満足して死ぬ
We will kill the enemy, and then we shall die, satisfied!
That shall be our hymn to Emloy, the god of war!
それこそが　戦いの神エムロイへの賛歌だ
Here, we have found our war!
我ら　ここに戦いを得たり
騎士ノーマ　討死に
The knight Norma has been slain!
Norma...
ノーマが…
東門　陥落
The east gate has fallen!
Civilians have entered combat!
民兵隊　戦闘に突入　援軍要請来てます
They're requesting reinforcements!
We have none left to send!
出せる兵士はもういない
No! No!
ダメよ　ダメ　ダメなの
No...
このままじゃ　私　わ　私
At this rate, I-I...
I'm going to go crazy!
おかしくなっちゃう
What's going on?
どういうことだ？
The souls of soldiers who fell on the battlefield
戦場で倒れた兵士の魂魄が　彼女の肉体を通して
are being sent to Emloy through her body.
エムロイの元へ召される
それが彼女に　媚薬のような作用をもたらしている
It affects her like an aphrodisiac might.
This looks bad.
まずくないですか？
Lelei, can we help her?
レレイ　どうしたらいい？
I believe all she has to do is fight.
戦いに身を任せればいいはず
Any word from the east gate?
東門から連絡は？
None.
ありません
We need to guide the reinforcements, too.
援軍を誘導する必要もあるし…
Where are our reinforcements?
Where are the men in green?
援軍は？緑の服の人たちは？
もうダメだ　後退を…
It's over! Retreat—
If this keeps up, they're going to break through the bulwarks, too!
このままでは　城門に続き　防塁も突破されます
If that happens, the city will be pillaged.
そうなれば　市内も蹂躙されます
You must order the people to evacuate!
今のうちに　住民の避難指示を
If only my knights were here...
妾の騎士団さえいれば…
Kuribayashi!
栗林
Yes, sir!
はい
Sorry, but could you stay with Rory?
すまないが　ロゥリィについていってくれ
Sergeant Kuwabara, take care of the rest.
桑原曹長　後は頼む
Roger.
了解
Rory, we're going.
ロゥリィ　行くよ　少しの間辛抱して
Just hang in there for a little longer.
早ぇ
Wow, she's fast.
我々も追うぞ　急げ
We're going after her! Hurry!
401st, this is Recon 3.
４０１　こちら３ラコン
The enemy has been engaged at the east gate.
敵は東門にて　戦闘中
Repeat, the enemy is at the east gate.
繰り返す　敵は東門
We will be marking the target with a flare.
目標は白色信号で知らせる　送れ
Over!
We'll reach the mission zone in five minutes.
あと５分で現地到着です
Yeah, got it.
わかった
Reports indicate that fighting has already begun inside the east gate.
報告によると　すでに東門の内部で戦闘になってるそうです
Head for ten o'clock.
１０時の方向　全機攻撃態勢を取れ
All units move into attack positions!
Roger!
了解
All units move into attack positions!
全機　攻撃態勢を取れ
We'll sweep in with the rising sun at our backs.
朝日を背に突入
後は二佐に任せる
The Lieutenant Colonel can handle the rest.
Start the music!
音楽を鳴らせ
Ride of the Valkyries
Why do all you guys sit on your helmets?
なんで鉄鉢を下に敷くんだ？
So we don't get our balls blown off!
タマを守るためだよ
Kuribayashi!
栗林
はい
Right!
Take off your V8s.
Ｖ８外しとけよ
なんでです？
Why?
お前　すぐ壊すだろう
You always break them.
I do not!
壊しませんよ
It's dawn and we don't need them anymore.
もう夜明けだから　必要ない
If you don't want to get yelled at, just take them off.
無駄に怒られたくなかったら　素直に外しとけ
一人残らず殺せ
Kill them all!
俺たちも続け
Follow his lead!
All units, this is Oscar 1.
各機　こちらオスカーワン
We've got friendlies inside the gate.
城門の中には味方がいる　外のみを殲滅せよ
Restrict your fire to the outside.
Give me your spear!
お前の槍　貸せ
Okay!
AA weapon on the wall.
城壁上に対空兵器
They're still loading.
まだ装填前です
Hunter 1, you are clear to engage target.
ハンター１　目標を攻撃せよ
ハンター１　了解
Hunter 1, roger!
Well done!
よくやった
When we get back, I'll buy you a beer.
戻ったら　ビールを奢る
Proper sighting.
正しい見出し　正しい引き付け　正しい頰付け
Proper leading.
Proper positioning.
コトリと落ちるように
Bring it straight down.
Look at all those explosions.
すごい爆発　あれも魔法？
Is that magic, too?
無理
Impossible.
Hey!
ちょっと？
Where are you going?
どこ行くの？
To get a closer look!
近くで見る
Damn it!
くそ
The Priestess of Emloy?
エムロイの神官？
つけ剣
Affix bayonets!
あのバカ
That idiot!
支援する
We'll provide support!
突撃にぃ　前へ
Forward...
Go!
テストゥド隊列
Tortoise formation!
Oops!
Fall back and regroup!
一旦退け　隊列　組み直せ
Grenade!
手榴弾
This is bad.
まずいな　あいつらのめり込みすぎてる
They've lost track of their surroundings!
What do we do?
どうします？
Don't let anybody get behind them, no matter what.
何があっても　後ろに敵を回り込ませるな
Defend their backs!
背後を守れ
Roger!
了解
みっ　認めんぞ　こんなものが戦いであってたまるか
I refuse to accept this...
This can't be called a war!
そうは思わんか　エムロイの神官よ
Don't you agree, Priestess of Emloy?
Answer me, Priestess of Emloy!
答えろ　エムロイの神官よ
Our leader...
首領が…
Don't panic! Regroup!
狼狽えるな　態勢を立て直せ
Recon 3, this is Hunter 1!
３レコン　こちらハンターワン
On the count of ten, we're going to wipe out the targets inside the gate.
これよりカウント１０で門内を掃討する
至急退避されたし
Evacuate immediately.
Repeat, we will now wipe out the enemies inside the gate.
繰り返す　これより門内を掃討する　至急退避されたし
Evacuate immediately.
十　九　八　七　六　五　四　三…
Ten, nine, eight, seven...
Six, five, four, three...
ちょっと　自分で走るから
Put me down! I can run on my own!
A monster...
化け物…
An iron pegasus?
鋼鉄の天馬
What is that?
何なんだ　あれは
Absolute violence that no human can withstand...
人が抗えない絶対的な暴力
すべてを叩き潰す力
The power to crush everything...
A power that denies pride, honor,
誇りも名誉も　すべてを否定する
and everything else.
It's over...
終わった
The brigands were wiped out?
盗賊が全滅？
Is this the goddess mocking us?
これは女神の蔑みなのか
人はなんて矮小で　無価値で　無意味なのか
How frail, worthless, and insignificant we humans are...
Drop!
降下
全周警戒
Keep a close eye on our perimeter!
Get all those who surrender in one place!
投降者を一ヶ所に集めろ
Rescue the survivors!
生存者の救出を
This one's still breathing!
こっち　まだ息がある
Colonel, this is Youga.
一佐　こちら用賀
The enemy force has been wiped out.
敵集団は壊滅　周囲に敵影なし　終わり
No other enemies in the vicinity.
Over.
Well done.
It's over, huh?
終わったか
Thank you.
ありがとう
You saved our town.
おかげで町は救われました
What army are you with?
あなた方はどこの軍隊なのですか？
We are the JSDF.
私たちは自衛隊です
All those brigands...
あれだけの盗賊が…全滅
And almost every single one is dead.
自衛隊とは…
Just what is this JSDF?
Thus, the JSDF Fought There!
It's over.
終わりましたか
The brigands were wiped out.
確かに盗賊は撃退した
Yes, we were victorious.
はい　我々の勝利です
違う
No.
It was the Priestess of Emloy, Rory, and the JSDF who won.
勝利したのはエムロイの使徒ロゥリィと自衛隊で　妾ではない
Not me.
And the JSDF is our enemy
そして　自衛隊は聖なるアルヌスを占拠し続けている我らが敵
which continues to occupy the holy hill of Alnus.
In intending to save Italica,
妾はイタリカを救うつもりで
have I not called in a far more terrifying force?
もっと恐ろしいものを引きずり込んだのではなかろうか
That iron pegasus and the powerful magics
一瞬にして盗賊を滅却した
that wiped the brigands out in but a moment...
あの鋼鉄の天馬と強大な魔導が
If they were turned towards Italica,
もし　それがこのイタリカに向いたとしたら
then both I
妾も…
and Myui, the countess of Formar,
フォルマル伯爵公女ミュイも簡単に虜囚となり
would be quickly turned into prisoners,
and one of the Empire's most important agricultural areas would fall to the enemy.
この帝都を支える穀倉自体は敵の物となる
And the people would welcome them with cheers and open arms.
住民たちはそれを歓喜の声で迎えるだろう
That's not true—
そんなことは…
Can you be so sure?
ないと言い切れるか
They were the ones who truly saved the town.
実際町を救ったのは彼らだぞ
If they were to demand our surrender,
もし彼らが開城を要求してきたら　妾は取りすがって慈悲を乞い
I might respond by falling to my knees and begging for mercy...
And kissing the soles of their feet.
足の甲にキスしてしまうかもしれない
We are grateful to you for rescuing Italica
イタリカ救援に感謝し　その対価の交渉を行いたい
and would like to negotiate your compensation.
The second article, the safety of a delegation, and its expenses,
第二の使節の往来の無事と諸経費に関しては慣例通りとする
will be taken care of in accordance with Imperial protocol.
And the third article, trading rights for the Alnus cooperative,
第三のアルヌス協同生活組合の貿易特権　それも問題ない
poses no problem, either.
But I'd like you to understand that the rights to the prisoners lie with us.
だが　捕虜の権利はこちら側にあると心得ていただきたい
"We understand that labor is necessary to rebuild Italica."
イタリカの復興に労働力が必要なのは理解した
"But we want assurances that they'll be treated humanely."
だが　人道的に扱う確約をいただきたい　と
He said.
"Humane...ly"?
ジンドウテキ？
To be treated well, as one would treat a friend,
友人　親戚　知人に対するように　無下には扱わないこと
relative, or acquaintance.
Would friends or relatives attack a peaceful town,
友人や親戚が平和に暮らす町を襲い　人々を殺め　略奪などするものか
pillaging it and killing its people?
Those are their rules.
それが彼らのルール
Understood.
了解した
That settles the matter of the treatment of the prisoners.
では　捕虜に関しては以上だ
All that's left is the military withdrawal and the treaty period.
残りは軍隊の退去と協定期間に関して
We have no problems with it as written.
条文通りで異存はない
Then that concludes the negotiations.
では　それで条件を結する
So, how'd it go?
どうなりましたか？
They took several prisoners,
捕虜数人と費用こちら持ちで　使節の仲介と無事の保障
and asked us to take care of any diplomatic delegation's security and expenses.
And a release from all trade taxes in Italica.
イタリカでの交易の租税免除だ
Those are rather small demands for a victor.
勝利者にしては少ない要求ですな
So will they occupy the city?
で　そのまま駐留して　ここも占領ですか？
They're leaving immediately.
直ちに退去するそうだ
Then they've barely gained anything out of this!
それでは向こうが丸損じゃないですか？
I've never heard of an army that would accept such conditions.
そんな条件を呑む軍隊など聞いたことが
Yes. To make them give up the natural rights of a victor
ああ　勝者に当然の権利を放棄させるとは恐ろしいほどの交渉能力だ
would take incredible negotiating skills.
I'd love to know what kind of magic Hamilton used.
ハミルトンがどんな魔法を使ったのか知りたいものだ
Her, and her.
あの子とあの子
And her, too.
それに　あっちの子だな
The one with a feather in her hair?
あの頭に羽がついた子ですか？
Yup.
そう
You've only picked women.
女の子ばかりですね
That's just a coincidence.
偶然だよ　偶然
That seems unlikely.
そうは思えませんが
偶然だって
It's a coincidence.
A coincidence, huh?
偶然ね
Yup. A coincidence!
そう　偶然
Well,
まあ　女の子をここに残すわけにはいかないというのは分かりますけど
I understand that we can't leave the girls here.
ありがとう
Goodbye! Thank you! Goodbye!
さようなら
ありがとう
Okay, we should head back, too.
じゃあっ　我々も帰りますかね
Huh? Where are the girls?
あれ　お嬢さん方は？
Accomplishing our original goal. Selling those dragon scales.
本来の目的の商談中
Oh, that's right. That's why we're here, isn't it?
それが目的でしたね…
Yup.
ああ　そのはずなのに…
Or it was supposed to be...
Why'd we get caught up in all this trouble?
なんでこんな面倒に巻き込まれたかなぁ
I want to sell this.
これを売りたい
Oh, is this a dragon scale?
これは竜の鱗ですか？
Lyudo the Merchant
From its size, I'd say a winged dragon?
大きさから翼竜ですな
Yes.
そう
And how many do you have?
で　いかほど？
Two hundred.
二百枚
Two hundred?!
二百枚！？
I just received release from all taxes in this territory.
さっき領内での交易租税の免除を受けた
You became a Special Merchant?
特権商人になられたと　おめでとうございます
Congratulations.
Then that would be 200 gold cinque pieces
ならば　シンク金貨二百枚とデナリ銀貨四千枚で
and 4,000 silver denarii.
But after the last battle, we've been low on silver.
ですが　先の戦いで銀貨が不足しておりましてな
I can pay you the 1,000 denarii immediately.
すぐに払える銀貨は千枚
And the rest?
残りは？
I can give you a draft for 2,000 immediately, but...
二千枚分は為替ならすぐにでも　ですが…
All right. I'll give you a discount of 1,000 denarii.
わかった　銀貨千枚分を割り引く
In exchange, I want information worth 1,000 denarii.
その代り　その千枚分で情報を集めてほしい
Information? Of what type?
情報？どのような
Information on the markets for 1,000 silver denarii?
相場の情報に銀貨千枚ですか？
If it's got a price, it's a product.
値がついた以上　なんでも商売だ
And our motto is
商品の品質はよりよいものを　が我々のモットーだろう
"top quality products," right?
I'm tired, Kurata.
眠いよ　倉田
I know the feeling.
無理もないですよ　大変でしたし
That was rough.
It was horrible.
大変どころじゃねえよ　疲れた
I'm exhausted.
Smoke in front of us!
前方に煙が見えます
More smoke?
また煙かよ
It's coming this way?
こっちに来る
The smoke's keeping me from getting a good look.
煙が邪魔でよく見えないな
I can see something!
見えました
What can you see?
何が
A tiara!
ティアラです
Oh, a tiara. Okay.
ああ　ティアラね
A tiara?!
ティ…ティアラ！？
Blonde hair!
金髪です
Blonde hair?
金髪？
Ringlets!
縦ロールです
Ringlets?
縦ロール！？
I've sighted one blonde girl with ringlets,
目標　金髪縦ロール一　男装の麗人一　後方に美人多数
one beautiful girl in boys' clothes,
and several hot chicks behind them!
Those are roses!
薔薇だな
薔薇です
They are roses!
That tri-colored rose crest...
三色の薔薇
The knights the princess spoke of?
姫様が言ってた騎士団か？
I've never actually seen a girl
俺　縦巻きロールの実物なんて初めて見ましたよ
with ringlets like that before.
So the ringlets girl is the yellow rose,
縦ロールが黄バラ様で
and the one with the short hair next to her is the white rose?
隣のショートが白バラ様ってとこか？
All units, alert status.
総員警戒
Hold up, old man.
おやっさん　待って
No overt shows of hostility.
総員　敵対行動は避けろ
It might violate the treaty.
協定違反になりかねない
Roger.
了解
Where did you come from?
どこから来た
We're returning from Italica.
我々　イタリカから帰る
To where?
どこへ
Alnus Ur—
アルヌス・ウル…
The Hill of Alnus?
アルヌスの丘だと
Old man, don't let any of our guys fire.
おやっさん　絶対にこっちから手を出させないでよ
Are you the enemy from another world?
貴様　異世界の敵か？
Um, excuse me.
ええと　失礼　部下が何かいたしましたかね
Has my man there done something to offend you?
Surrender!
降伏なさい
Now, calm down.
まっ　まあ　落ち着いて
We can work this out—
話せば…
お黙りなさい
Silence!
Hold fire! Hold fire! Hold fire!
待って　待て待て
Run!
逃げろ
For now, just get out of here!
とにかく　今逃げろ
Get going!
さあ　行け
unmei niwa sakaraenai ne deatteshimatta
I guess I just can't fight my fate - we've already met!
運命には逆らえないね
出会ってしまった
何があるかわからないけれど
nani ga aru ka wakaranai keredo
I don't know what might happen,
君と出かけよう
kimi to dekakeyou
but I'm heading out with you!
心踊る遠い景色は
kokoro odoru tooi keshiki wa
There's something a bit different
なんだか違って
nandaka chigatte
about the far off scenery,
doa o akete itsumo no choushi sa
But once we open the door, we're back to
ドアを開けていつもの調子さ
どうぞよろしく
douzo yoroshiku
our usual pace, so let's keep on together!
mada kimerarenai sanpo koosu
We still can't decide which course to walk
まだ決められない散歩コース
いろんなものが多すぎて
iron na mono ga oosugite
There are just too many things to consider.
光りの渦に吸い込まれて
hikari no uzu ni suikomarete
Pulled into a whirlpool of light,
また迷ってるの
mada mayotteru no
We're still undecided!
走り抜けたあの瞬間は
hashirinuketa ano shunkan wa
Amidst a sweet, sweet scent,
amai amai kaori no naka de
We can feel a new future within this place.
甘い甘い香りの中で
arata na mirai koko ni kanjiteru
Upon a song, disappearing high into the sky,
新たな未来　ここに感じてる
tondekieru uta ni noseta
But the moment we manage to run on through
飛んで消える二人の星座
sora e sora e kirei na hoshi ni
I'll cast a spell that sparkle brightly,
空へ空へきれいな星に
キラキラ光るように
kirakira hikaru you ni mahou kakeru kara
I'll cast magic which shines bright
魔法をかけるから
Episode 7  The Princess's Decision
次回　「ゲート」
Next time on GATE:
"The Princess's Decision."
「皇女の決断」